<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open Source on LinuxDive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open Source on LinuxDive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Linux Powers Government Infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/government-linux-adoption/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/government-linux-adoption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Governments worldwide have increasingly adopted Linux as a cornerstone of their digital infrastructure. From critical systems that manage citizen services to national defense initiatives, Linux provides the stability, security, and transparency that public institutions require.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;security-and-transparency&#34;&gt;Security and Transparency&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Government agencies need to ensure that their systems are secure and auditable. Linux&amp;rsquo;s open-source nature allows governments to inspect the code themselves, eliminating the black-box problem inherent in proprietary systems. This transparency is crucial for citizens who deserve to know how their government&amp;rsquo;s technology works.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Linux Community: How Millions Collaborate to Build Technology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-open-source-community/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/linux-open-source-community/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Linux is not just software—it&amp;rsquo;s a global community of developers, maintainers, users, and organizations collaborating across borders, timezones, and languages. This ecosystem has created something unprecedented in technology history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;distributed-development-at-scale&#34;&gt;Distributed Development at Scale&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Tens of thousands of developers contribute to Linux development. The kernel alone receives thousands of patches monthly from hundreds of developers. This distributed, asynchronous model has proven remarkably effective.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;mentorship-and-knowledge-transfer&#34;&gt;Mentorship and Knowledge Transfer&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Linux community has developed sophisticated mechanisms for onboarding new contributors:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
